We saw how we can grant a user or group
specific access to a part of a database
in the previous video. Let's look further into
some granting options. Here is one scenario:
an administrator may want to save time in overall
database administration through not only granting
a role to someone, but also giving that person,
or sometimes group, the option to grant the same
permission to others. I have a blank query window
open and I'm going to type a GRANT statement,
explain it, and then execute it. I will type
GRANT EXECUTE ON GetDepartment to procTester
WITH GRANT OPTION. Before I run this statement,
let's go through its details. GRANT grants a
privilege, in this case Execute, on an object.
The object, in this example, GetDepartment,
is a stored procedure, which we will detail later
in this course. procTester is a user account that
I added to this SQL Server instance and then to
this database. The WITH GRANT OPTION clause gives
this account, procTester, the ability to grant
execute privileges on this stored procedure to
other users and groups. While this grant is a
convenience for allowing people to help control
access to an object, of course administrators
need to show discretion as to who they grant these
options to when granting permissions on a resource
as we want to make sure, as we execute this,
only those who know how to handle permissions
properly grant permissions to others.